Sinners?
罪人？
We are?
私たちが？
Lykos?
リコスさん？
Dear me, it's already here.
…来てしまった…
Chakuro...
チャクロ…
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
Translator
字 幕 入 力
ssnake
ssnake
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
Timing
字 幕 編 集
zwc1991
zwc1991
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた…
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた…
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
さ  き
さ  き
その先へ　その未来へ
その先へ　その未来へ
導かれたのなら
導かれたのなら
幾千の声　空想の地へ
幾千の声　空想の地へ
舵を切って行こうとした
舵を切って行こうとした
バラード
バラード
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
Help!
助けて！
Help me!
誰か〜！
Everybody listen!
みんな！
Enter the building as soon as possible!
早く建物の中に入りなさい
Taisha-sama!
タイシャ様〜！
Move!
早く！
Then flee to the specialized building!
そこから専門棟へ避難なさい
Huh?
ん？
What's up?
何かあったのか？
It's strange.
様子がおかしい
What's hell there? Hey.
何の騒ぎだぁ？一体よぉ
Dunno.
さあな
Hey.
お？
See that guy, he's wearing something strange.
見ろよ　何だ？ あの格好
Isn't he a fellow of the girl in that island?
島の女の仲間じゃねえか？
Let's knock him over.
捕まえてみるか
Hey, you.
おい　てめえ！
Be here.
ちょっと来いよ
We wanna get to the world outside...
俺たちさあ　外の世界に出たいんだけど
What?
ん？
Whah?
…え？
Buki!
ブキ！
Hey Bukiii!
おい　ブキィ！
Hey.
おい
What's up?
何だよ
Let me out, it's strange outside.
…出せ　外の様子がおかしい
Hurt...
イタ…
Sami.
サミ
The angle of death
殺戮の天使は
had torn our paradise to bits
大きな爪で
with his huge claw.
私たちの楽園を引き剥がしていった
Sami, we have to run away.
サミ　逃げなきゃ…
I'll never do this again.
今日だけだよ
Sami, you're not heavy at all.
サミ　全然重たくないよ…
You are as light as 3 years ago.
三年前と変わらない
Sorry for making fun with you yesterday.
昨日は意地悪言って　ごめんね…
Sami...
サミ…
Finally the judgment is passed on us.
ついに審判が下ったのだ
Sami and Chakuro are still in the farm!
サミやチャクロたちがまだ農園に
It's wrong...
…間違ってる…
These people...
この人たちは
They are not the sinners who should perish!
滅びていい罪人なんかじゃない！
What's the hell is that?
なんだ…　これ…
φάλαινα
ファレナ
In the mission of annihilating the sinners of the whale,
鯨の罪人殲滅という任務において
the most important thing is to take records.
肝要なることは　記録を取ることである
We need to show the end of them, the heretic,
彼ら異端の民の末路は
to the people in our empire...
我が国　いや
No, but to point out the path that all mankind in the world should take.
全世界の人類が取るべき道筋を指し示す
Record it scrupulously.
克明に記録せよ
Lykos?
リコスさん？
No you can't.
駄目ですよっ
Wait!
待って！
I have no choice but to fight.
私が戦うしかない
Even if... it means that I have to betray that person.
たとえ…　あの人を裏切っても
Hey you.
あなたたち…
Suo-sama.
スオウ様
Are you OK?
大丈夫ですか？
Yes.
はい
But there are still injured people in the farm.
でも　まだ怪我した人が農園に…
Suo-sama.
スオウ様
Everybody...
みんな…
Suo,
スオウ
please listen calmly.
落ち着いて聞いてください
It seems Taisha-sama...
タイシャ様が…
has died...
亡くなられたそうです…
The presbytery keeps silence in such a situation.
この事態に長老会は沈黙しています
Why... why we have to face this tragedy?
なぜ…こんなことになっているのか
Shinono-sama...
シノノ様…
Please gather together in the central square,
みんなを中央広場へ集めて
and ask the vigilante group to protect everybody.
自警団に守らせてください
As far as they are human,
向こうも人間なのでしょう？
they should not allow such violence.
こんな暴虐が…許されるわけがない！
Since the presbytery doesn't take a move,
長老会が動かないのであれば
I will solve it by negotiation!
私が話し合いで解決します！
Damn! You're making fool of us.
畜生…　馬鹿にしやがって
Take this, asshole!
なめんな　クソ野郎！
Stop!
よせ！
Aijiro!
アイジロ！
No, it's impossible.
だ…駄目だあ…
sentikinesis
サイミア
They're using their thymia...
あいつらの情念動の使い方
in a murderer way.
人殺しの使い方だ
They're demons! It's crazy!
鬼だよ　おかしいんだよ！
S... stop that shit!
ふ…ふざけんなよ
Keep away! If you get any closer!
それ以上…近づくんじゃねえ！
Nibi
ニビ
Oni!
オウニ！
Oni! Buki and Aijiro died!
オウニ！　ブキとアイジロが死んじゃった
They got killed!
殺されちゃったよ！
So that's it...
…こんなもんかよ
That is the world we have longed for, outside the sea of sand,
俺やこいつらが憧れてきた　砂の海の外は
where the masked guys can trample our dream easily.
顔の見えない連中が　簡単に俺たちの夢を踏みにじる
So that is the world!
そんな世界だったのかよ
Oni!
オウニ！
I don't care anymore...
もういい…
I care no more...
こんな世界は…
about that world!
もう　どうでもいい！
So we have everybody here?
これで全員でしょうか？
Suo-sama!
スオウ様！
I'm Ginshu from the vigilante group.
自警団のギンシュでありますっ！
Our task is to protect the peace of mud whale.
自警団の任務は泥クジラの平穏を守ること
We should give them as good as we got!
やられたらやり返すのみでありますっ！
You should never kill the opposite.
…相手は殺してはいけない
It's an endless circle if we return violence to violence.
暴力に暴力で返せばキリがありません
There is no reason for us to be attacked.
我々には攻撃を受ける理由がない
There must be something misunderstood.
この事態には必ず誤解がある
We are solving this misunderstanding.
その誤解を解くのです
I believe Taisha-sama would solve it in this manner.
タイシャ様なら　きっとそうするはず
Man...
うわ…
Taisha-sama...
タイシャ様…
Is it fine?
これで　いいのですか？
Is this the only way, we can deal with it?
こうするしか…ないのですか？
No more I wanna see.
なにも見たくない
Sami, it's fine right?
サミ…もういいよね…
Let's close our eyes together, like this.
このまま一緒に目瞑ってるね…
Then I don't have to see stuffs disgusting me any more, right?
そしたら…もう嫌なもの見なくてすむよね…？
Chakuro!
チャクロー！
Where's our brother?
お兄ちゃんは？
Kids...
チビたち…
Ah, wait!
あ…　待って！
Stop it!
やめて！
Don't do anything with the kids, please.
チビに何もしないであげて
I beg you...
おねが…
S... STOP!!
や…やめろ～！
Stop it!
やめてよ
Stop it please!
もうやめてよ！
The same skin color with Lykos...
リコスと同じ肌の色
Brother!
お兄ちゃんっ！
You idiot!
バカ　お前らっ…
Chakuro!
チャクロー！
Chakuro run away!
チャクロ　逃げろ！
Don't touch Sami!
サミに触るな！
Keep out!
近づくな！
Stop.
よせ
She is...
あの人は—
So you have survived.
生きておられたのか
νοῦς
ヌース
λύκος
λύκος
It's said that Lykos the nous
魂形「リコス」は
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
received an assault during its way to the annihilation of Fallaina,
ファレナ殲滅に向かう途中で襲撃を受け
and nobody survived.
全滅したとのことでしたが
Is there any other survival?
他に生き残りは？
Hey, what the hell is it?
おい　どういうことだよ
Shhh.
しっ
This way.
こちらへ
σκύλος
σκύλος
Let's return to Skulax.
スキロスにお戻りください
Leave me alone.
放して
I won't return to you.
私はあなたたちの所へは戻らない
νοῦς
魂形による制御から離れてご乱心なさったか？
You must get disturbed after leaving the control of nous.
ヌース
After all, you are the younger sister
あなたはファレナ殲滅作戦総指揮官の
of the general commander of the annihilation of Fallaina.
妹君であられるというのに
It's nothing to do with my brother!
兄はもう関係ない！
Has he searched me for a single time?
兄は私を捜してくれましたか？
Has he told my parents about my potential death?
私が死んだかもしれないことを　両親に報告してくれましたか？
Even if I return to the empire,
私は国へ戻ったって
I'm just a puppet with neither mind nor name!
心も名前もない人形でしかない！
Wait a moment, please.
お待ちなさい
αράχνη
αράχνη
Tell Arakhne, captain of Skulax.
スキロスのアラフニ司令へ伝令を
Lykos...
リコス
Who...
君は…
Who are you?
君は誰なの？
Answer me.
答えてよ
He has the same skin color with you...
あいつだって　君と同じ肌の色で…
Hey hey hey!
おいおいお〜い
How dare you lose it, rubbish!
やられてんじゃねえよ　クズ！
λύκος
λύκος
No. 32 of Lykos!
「リコス」の32！
You are alive!
生きてたのかよぉ
λιοντάρι
λιοντάρι
Ryotari...
リョダリ…
You were on Skulax?
あなた　スキロスに乗ってたの？
I heard that Lykos had been wiped out, I was worried.
「リコス」は全滅って聞いてたし　心配したぜ
You don't even have such a mind.
そんな心　あなたにはないでしょ
Bingo!
アタリ〜
There's no time for me to worry you!
心配してる暇なんてあるかよ！
I was sent to the massacre!
大虐殺の現場に派遣されることになったんだぜ？
I was looking forward it all my heart that I could care nothing else!
楽しみで楽しみで　ほかのことなんか考えてらんねえよ！
Fallaina is the best, the paradise!
ファレナは最高の楽園だぁ！
Full of prey, no resistance!
無抵抗の獲物だらけなんだぁ〜
See!
見ろよ
I can even kill such a cute girl!
こ～んな可愛い子をブチ殺してもいいんだぜ～
Don't touch Sami!
サミに触るな！
Cry... Crying!
な…泣いてる
This guy is crying!
こいつ　泣いてる！
I seldom see anyone crying!
泣いてる奴なんかめったに見られない
I wanna make you cry more!
もっと泣かしたい
I wanna break you more!
壊したい
I wanna kill...
殺したい…
Ryotari,
リョダリ！
I won't let you do harm to him.
その子に手は出させない！
No. 32...
「32」…
Why interrupt me?
…なんで邪魔すんの…？
You mean I can kill you too?
お前も殺していいってこと？
It's Skulax.
スキロス
νοῦς
ヌース
λύκος
λύκος
We have secured Lykos ths nous.
魂形「リコス」は確保された
The soldiers should return.
兵は帰還せよ
Chakuro!
チャクロ！
Lion guy, we finished today.
獅子坊　今日はこれまでだ
Get back.
帰るぞ
Hey what about this guy?
ねえ　こいつはどうするの？
Shouldn't we bring her back?
連れて帰るんでしょ？
No, I won't return!
嫌だ！　私は戻らない！
Hah?
はあ？
You know it's impossible.
んなことできるわけないじゃん
What're you going to do in Fallaina at all?
第一　ファレナでお前が何すんだよ？
All the guys here will die after all.
ここの奴らは　どうせ全員死ぬんだぞ？
Leave me!
放して！
Hey you...
お前…！
Listen to me, the idiots over there.
そこのおバカさんたち〜♪
Listen, listen!
伝言　伝言〜！
όρκα
όρκα
It's the pierrot of general commander Orca.
オルカ総司令の道化だ
We leave No. 32 in Fallaina.
32番はファレナへ残すこと
The general commander said
総司令は妹君を
we shall treat his younger sister as a sample
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
サンプルにすると言われた
We should call her
これから彼女を
Sample No. 4 of Skulax from now on.
スキロスサンプルの4番と呼ぶように…
That's all!
だって〜！
How... How cruel he is!
ひ…ひでえ！
That's what he did after knowing his younger sister is still alive!
死んだと思ってた妹が生きてたってのに
Hey! Sample No. 4!
おい！　サンプル４番！
You are abandoned by your bro!
お前　兄貴に見捨てられたってよォ！
Go back, go back.
か〜えろ　帰ろ
Hey, pick me up!
お〜い　乗せろ
I will be here again, Sample No. 4!
また来るわ　サンプル4番！
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
I wanna see how strange you will be after get influenced by Fallaina!
んで　ファレナのせいでお前がおかしくなってくとこを
You have a name, don't you?
名前ならあるわよ
Λύκος
λύκος
Lykos, embroidered on your clothes.
あなたの洋服に「リコス」って刺繍してあった
όρκα
όρκα
Orca-sama.
オルカさま
Do you remember me?
私を覚えておられますか？
Your sister's friend.
あなたの妹のお友達です
Making your sister a guinea pig, didn't you be too cruel?
妹を実験台にするなんて　冷酷すぎやしませんか？
I have heard that if you succeed in this operation,
あなた様は　今回の作戦が成功すれば
you will be appointed as the governor of a state.
州の総督に任ぜられるとか
That is, to put it simply,
それって　つまり
you are sacrificing your sister for your career, right?
出世のために妹を犠牲にしたってことですよねぇ
I don't want to move the empire.
私は国を動かしたいんじゃない
My purpose is out of it.
目的はもっとほかにある
Taisha-sama...
タイシャ様…
Oni!
オウニ！
What... Why you are in such a mess?
お…おまえ　どうしたその格好
Give me remedies.
薬くれよ
You are full of bloods, are you wounded?
その血…怪我なの？
Remedies are for my friends.
薬は仲間のぶん
After 7 days...
7日後…
What?
ん？
They will come again.
あいつらがもう一度来る
Their purpose this time is the rescue of the ship where that girl was on.
あの女がいた船の回収が今回の目的
Next time will be the attack of mud whale.
泥クジラへの襲撃は次らしい
How... How did you know that?
な…なんでそんなこと分かるんだよ？
I made them tell me?
…吐かせた
Ma... made them?
は…吐かせた？
I killed them all except two.
二人だけ生かして　あとは殺した
You...
お前…
The two guys are in the same age as us.
生かした奴らは両方とも　歳は俺たちと変わらない
Why you hit him?
なんでぶつんだよ！
How you dare doing things such as torture...
拷問だなんて　お前らよくもそんなことを…
For all of us, isn't it!
みんなのためじゃないか！
Oni is doing nothing wrong.
オウニは悪くないよ
We will all be killed if Oni doesn't do this for us!
オウニがやらなきゃ　みんな殺されてたんだ！
You made Oni to do all the dirty stuffs...
汚いことは全部　オウニがやってくれたのに…
Enough.
もういい
Go, Kicha.
キチャ　行くぞ
Wa.. Hey, wait!
お… おい　待て
Stop doing things alone!
勝手に動くな！
Prisoners should be hold by the vigilante group...
捕虜は自警団…
Oh no, give them to me!
…あっいや　俺に預けろ！
I only trust my friends.
俺は仲間しか信用しない
The funeral was held as early as the next day.
葬儀は翌日早々に行われた
Although it is forbidden to cry at the funeral,
葬儀で泣くことは禁じられていたが
we could not help but crying.
私たちは　それを守れなかった
I was always... wanted to change the fate
ずっと…　「印」の短命を直してあげたかった…
of the short lives of Shirushi for you.
私は　サミや皆が
Since I can't bear it if Sami and others
私より先にいなくなるのが…
leave me before I die.
耐えられなかったから…
Even without leaving a single word...
…言葉もない
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
I failed to protect Sami.
俺が　サミを守ってあげられなくて
It was a sunny day.
その日は快晴で
The sight of the sand burial was really beautiful.
砂葬の光景は　とても美しかった
I would like to make it
こんなに悲しいことが　この世にあるなら
the last sight of my life,
この景色を最後に目に焼き付けたまま
if I have to face such a sad thing in this world.
私の命なんか　ここで終わってしまえばいい
I thought.
そう思った
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
虫の唄
虫の唄
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう